You
Yes
money. That's what I'm doing every day. That's what I'm doing every day. But I think these
things you talked about, which we brought to fruition, NVLink Fusion, working together
on optics. I mean, I think the era of agents and kind of your new platform now, I think
it's ideally suited. I mean, NVLink Fusion, we had this idea years ago, right? But I think
it was a little ahead of its time. And now, and I wanted to see if you agree when you
think about kind of your platform and then some of the custom networking and compute
needs that our customers have and the ability and the need to interoperate and work together.
It seems like the time is now between Marvell and NVIDIA to really go enable our customers
to have that flexibility that they're looking for and really use the era of agents to scale
our platforms together. Yeah, you know, ultimately, I do think that if you buy nothing but NVIDIA,
that's okay. Okay, I mean, if, but if you absolutely must design your own ASICs, we're
still happy having NVIDIA be inside that data center. And so, you know, you don't have to
buy everything from us, just buy something from us. You know, we're happy to support
you and support the customer. And so, so I think that between the two of us, you have
the benefit of a general purpose, very high efficiency, you know, a system that is very
well built, starting with, you know, of course, Vera Rubin, but anything that you want to
extend to specialize, you can do so as well, which is the reason why your customers of
mind NVIDIA is in AWS, Marvell is in AWS, NVIDIA is in all of the clouds. And it's wonderful
to see Marvell expand into all of these different clouds.
Yeah, great. Thanks. Hey, one last one for you.
Just leave some business for me. You know, look, we're your best sales people right
now. We're your best sales person working together. Final question for you. A lot of
my talk is about some of the transition, especially as you go to inside the rack from copper to
optical. It's obviously not going to be a one zero. It's going to take, you know, there's
time and there's different use cases. But how do you see that playing out right now,
the transition from copper to optics, and maybe how we can work together there too?
We should use copper as much as we can for as long as we can, but copper has its limits.
Copper has its limits with bandwidth and also with distance. And so ultimately, the right
strategy is to scale up with copper as long as you can. After that, you scale up further
with optics and you scale out with optics and you scale across with optics. And so you
use optics wherever you must, you use copper wherever you can. And so I think that intersection
is going to continue for a long time. Here's the bottom line is, in the next five, ten
years, we're going to use a ton of copper and we're going to use tons and tons of optics.
And so these data centers are part of infrastructure now. And the reason why I say that AI is now
useful, useful AI has arrived is because now AI is profitable and tokens are profitable.
When token production is profitable, everybody wants to make more tokens, which is the reason
why Marvell's demand is so high, is our demand is so high, because everybody wants to produce
more tokens because it's used all over the place by agents.
Absolutely. Well, I think you touched on a bunch of things I'm going to cover later.
If you want to do the rest of my presentation, you can.
So ladies and gentlemen, it's beautiful slides, you know, just sit right there.
You take it from here. All right, Jensen Juan. Good to see you, brother. All right, take care.
Okay, you guys, thank you. Thank you, Jensen. Bye, Marvell.
All right. Outstanding. Outstanding. Super fun to have Jensen here, as always.
All right. So we've been talking a lot about connectivity. Jensen, I just covered this.
So let's dive in now, right? Let's go one level deeper. So AI infrastructure spans every distance.
It spans from hundreds or even 1,000 kilometers between data centers to just millimeters inside
the package. Every one of those distances, it requires a different solution. It's a different
technology, different engineering team. It's a completely different set of experts.
And in many cases, it's a different supply chain. So these are not variations of the same problem.
What you have here is fundamentally different engineering challenges. And that's what we're
going to walk through next. All right, so let's start with the longest distance. Jensen referred
to this. This is scale across connecting data centers together. Now, every major cloud provider
has hundreds of data centers around the world. And all those data centers need to communicate
with each other. This is fundamentally a long distance connectivity problem. We're talking
about lengths that can span hundreds or even 1,000 kilometers. This requires very specific,
very complex technology called coherent modulation. At the heart of it is a specialized digital signal
processor or DSP. It's designed to push enormous amounts of data, cross fiber optic cables over
very long distances with extremely high reliability. There's only a few companies in the world that
build these coherent DSPs. And we're one of them. Marvell has been a leader in this technology
for many generations. We build optical modules that contain all the electronics needed to drive
and modulate the laser and transmit data over long distances. So I've got a little show and tell here
in my pocket. I'm not holding up a chip this time. I'm holding up an optical module.
This is one of our coherent optical modules. This is an incredibly complex piece of engineering.
At Marvell, we build the entire module. This is ours. It includes the advanced node CMOS DSP.
It's among the most complex chips, just the DSP alone that we design at Marvell.
But it also incorporates inside our fourth generation silicon photonics technology.
That's inside here. We've been developing that technology in production for a decade
on silicon photonics. It also includes our own broadband analog components that we designed,
which is designed in silicon germanium. So Marvell pioneered this technology,
starting with 100 gigabits per second a decade ago, then moving to 400 gig and now
shipping 800 gig in volume. And later this year, we'll be sampling the world's first
1.6 terabit 2 nanometer coherent optical solution. And that couldn't come in a better time.
Demand for bandwidth has never been greater. All right, now let's go inside the data center.
So these data centers can be very large, spanning hundreds of meters, and they contain racks
and racks of compute servers. Now, each rack typically has a switch at the top
with servers connected into that switch. Those rack level switches connect to the spine,
and then the core switches. This creates the network fabric that ties the entire data center
together. And all of that is connected through fiber optic cables. Now once again, optical modules
drive data transmission over those fiber optic cables. But this time the modulation scheme is
different. Instead of coherent technology, we use a more power optimized modulation technology,
which is called PAM4. So the two key semiconductor solutions for this part of the market are the
PAM4 chip set inside the module, and then the cloud switching infrastructure that ties the data center
together. Marvell builds both. Starting with the PAM4 chip set, we build the industry's leading
PAM4 DSP solution. And also the high speed analog components that go around them, including
transimpedance amplifiers, or TIAs, and laser drivers. These are also in Silicon Germanium,
by the way. And we've led the industry through every major transition of PAM technology, starting
at 50 gig, 100 gig, 200, 400, and 800. Then last year, we began ramping Marvell's 1.6T 3nm PAM4
solutions, leading the industry's transition to 1.6T connectivity. Now for ethernet switching,
Marvell has a similarly complete portfolio of products from 12.8 terabits to 51.2 terabits.
And today, we announced our new 100T ethernet switch, specifically designed for AI data centers
with the industry's lowest power. Woo! Special announcement for Computex. We waited. So you
put it all together, we provide a complete solution for connectivity inside the data center.
Now let's move inside the rack. The goal here is to connect the largest possible number of processors
together in a full any-to-any configuration. In other words, every processor can communicate
directly with every other processor. And Jensen talked about this. The first company to bring
this architecture to market was NVIDIA with NVL72, named for the 72 GPUs connected together inside
a single rack. And this required a completely different approach to connectivity. It was a
different class of switch and the ability to drive very high-speed signals over copper-backed
planes inside the rack. So today, this is not the domain of optics. This is the domain of copper.
And the core differentiator here is the electrical CERDES technology, not the optical.
Now Marvell also has leading electrical CERDES at 200 gigabits per second today. And we've
demonstrated already over the last couple of years 400 gigabits per second for the future.
So we're building this CERDES technology into our customers' custom silicon and their XPUs
and also into our own scale-up switches. All right, now let's go all the way inside the package.
Here we're not talking about meters anymore. We're talking about millimeters. And you might
not actually think about this as a connectivity challenge. But today, most advanced chips have
multiple chiplets inside the package. So when you have 2.5D or 3D packaging, it's fundamentally a
connectivity technology, actually. And it allows these chiplets to sit very close together inside
a package and communicate through ultra-high-speed, short-reach, die-to-die interfaces. And Marvell
has leading die-to-die CERDES and leading capability in advanced packaging, allowing our
customers to build some of the most complex, unique, multi-die chips in the industry.
So as you can see, connectivity for AI data centers requires a very broad portfolio of
technologies. Each distance requires a very different solution. And Marvell has the industry's
most complete portfolio, from millimeters to kilometers. Every hop, every distance. And it
turns out having all of those capabilities under one roof is unusual. It's unique. When we go and
compete, normally there's a different set of companies that we compete against in each one
of these categories across these different distances. But this is what makes us unique.
We're the one-stop shop. We're the leader across the entire connectivity stack. And that brings us to
the next major challenge facing the industry. So what you probably notice as I describe these
different solutions in the last couple of slides is there's different solutions for different
distances and that some of those connections today are optical and some of those connections today
are electrical. And it's actually defined by distance. And so the connections on the left side
of this chart are optical today. That means they use fiber optic cables to transmit light with
complex electronics on either side of the cable to drive and modulate the laser that's transmitting
that light. Connections on the right side of this are electrical. So they use copper cables,
or just copper traces that are printed on the circuit board, or even microscopic copper routing
inside the package. So the common theme here is copper. And in the middle, you see the wall,
the copper wall. And the wall is defined by the longest distance you can transmit a signal over
copper. So before you have to move to an optical, before you have to move to an optical connection.
So this is an important distinction because copper is simple and it's low cost. And as Jensen said,
you want to use it for as long as you can. It's very practical. But optics and optics is more
complicated. It requires lasers, photonics, complex electronics. So it's a bigger lift,
but it's going to be needed. And the copper wall, what I'm here to tell you today is it's about to
move. It's going to move again. And it's going to take over the rack itself. So this is creating
an explosion in demand for the optical industry. And incredibly complex engineering challenges
are coming along the way. So why is this happening? So it's not just somebody's preference to go do
this. This is physics. The distance a signal can travel over a copper cable is inversely proportional
to the bandwidth. So every time you double the bandwidth, you have to cut the distance in half.
Today, the highest speed production systems in the world run at 200 gigabits per second per
lane, just to give you an example. So at that bandwidth, the cable length is limited to roughly
two and a half meters. Now, by comparison, systems running at 100 gig could use about five meter
cables. And the height of the rack is about two meters. So once you account for all the routing
inside the rack, two and a half meters is right at the limit. So when we move to 400 gig, we can no
longer fully connect the rack with copper. So the wall is moving. And it's moving now.
Going forward, even the connections within the rack will become optical. And the whole industry
knows this is coming. So we've been preparing for this moment, not just Marvell, but the industry.
And you see this in Taiwan, by the way, and the supply chain and the ramp up that's happening.
The ramifications for this are actually enormous, because each time the wall moves one step to the
right, the number of connections that you have goes up by at least an order of magnitude. So it's
creating this explosion in demand, as I mentioned, and the optical supply chain needs to scale up
massively and be ready. But we've seen this movie before. Okay, I mean, 20 years ago, and I remember
this when state of the art was 10 gigabits per second inside the data center, 10 gig. And we
use copper cables all across the data center. Optics back then was reserved for just very,
very long distances. It was essentially like a telecom technology. But when the wall moved,
the optics industry actually rose to the challenge. And today, all the hyperscale data centers in the
world, they're all optically connected. And as we saw in that transition, it did require new
solutions. You couldn't use the same power hungry kind of telecom approach, which is where Pam four
came in. It's optimized for power, density and reach, and requirements specifically tuned to
inside the data center. And Marvell was one of the key innovators there. So we're about to see
the same wave of innovation needed as optics moves inside the rack. And that's what the technology
called co package optics or CPO, you hear a lot about this now, I'm going to tell you more.
CPO is a technology where we bring the optical connections all the way to the package itself,
right next to the compute, either the custom compute, or the switching silicon. And the fundamental
challenge we're solving with CPO is density and power. Now remember, the number of connections
inside the rack is like 10x, the number of connections between the racks. So we try it.
So if you just try to use the same optical technology used across the racks in the data center,
you wouldn't have enough power, you wouldn't have enough physical space, you cannot fit all these
standard optical modules and cables as they are today, it just doesn't work. It's not possible.
So the industry has been inventing this co package optics concept, which brings the optical fiber
right to the package, it tightly couples the electronics that drive the signal over the fiber
directly with the custom compute or switching silicon. So this is a massive change. And
what's hard because you're combining some of the most advanced technologies in the chip industry,
leading edge CMOS, silicon photonics, advanced packaging, optical interconnect,
all manufactured in this in a small tightly integrated system. So complexity is very high,
but it's the only way to continue scaling bandwidth and overcome this limitation that I
talked about with copper while reducing power at the same time. So this is where the industry's
headed. And this is one of the reasons that Marvell has invested for more than a decade
in silicon photonics, optical DSPs, all the analog broadband components around it,
and all the advanced packaging, you need to pull this off. It needs to all come together actually
in CPO. So this isn't some futuristic thing, guys. Okay, it's happening now. And in fact,
I brought a couple of Marvell examples with me today. So let's do a quick, a quick show and tell.
Okay. Okay, so over here, you have a traditional ethernet switch. This is our 100 t tera link
switch that we announced today. And you guys are the first to see it actually, everybody here in
the room. You can see the switch in the middle of the board. Copper traces inside the PCB carry
the signal to the front panel, which is here. And this is where all the optical modules plug in.
Now let's move over here. This is a CPO based switch right here. Now notice that there's still
the switch silicon in the middle. That's right in the center of the die of the package. In this case,
this is our 51.2 t switch. And all around the edges are 16 3.2 t optical engines. So the 16
times 3.2, you get 51.2. So this is, this is the fibers directly attached now to the, to these
engines. It's not to the front panel. So we've completely eliminated the copper traces on the
PCB light comes directly out of the package. Okay, this is a very, very complex, complex piece of
engineering. And it was very, it was very cool to be able to show this off today. Okay, so
co package optics is here and the industry is scaling up to meet the challenge. And as we've
seen time and time again, every time we reach a physical barrier, we break through it with technology
and innovation. In this case, by replacing copper with fiber, because unlike electrons traveling
over copper wires, the distance that photons can carry a signal through glass is largely unrelated
to the bandwidth. So as AI infrastructure demands even higher transmission speeds and needs to scale
to larger and more complex systems, spanning millions of processors woven together now, not
thousands or hundreds, optical connectivity will increasingly become the de facto solution. So
the real question becomes, what does it take to deliver optics across the full AI infrastructure
stack? What's it going to take? Well, it starts with recognizing there is no single technology
for the entire data center. It's not how this works. There's no one size fits all, there's no
one size fits all solution. There's no shortcuts. There's no easy way to the end here. There's not
a single architecture modulation scheme, frequency band, you know, unique technology that's going
to do it all. There's no free lunch. That's why we are pursuing a bunch of different unique
optical paths across every distance to get here. Each one of these technologies that I have up
here is optimized for a different design point. Each one enables a critical part of the infrastructure
and addressing different requirements for density, bandwidth, and power and integration
all across the stack. So if optical interconnect is the underlying technology for which next
generation AI infrastructure is built, then Marvell is building the broadest portfolio with the
deepest bench in the industry. But no company can deliver this transformation alone. And as Jensen
talked about earlier, it takes an ecosystem to get here. So like I said, technology innovation
is great. It's part of the challenge, but not all of it. But demonstrating this at scale is really
what matters. And at this point, if you're just operating on a PowerPoint or a demo, POC, press
release, it's not going to get you there. Customers need solutions now that are ready. They're
reliable. They need to be manufacturable and be ready to deploy at scale. So Marvell and our
ecosystem partners have been doing this for a long time. We've already shipped hundreds of
millions of DSPs. We've accumulated through our volumes tens of billions of device hours
of data in the field. This experience matters because these products have to work not just in
the lab, but in the world's largest data centers at very high volume and very reliably for years.
So that requires investing ahead in the manufacturing ecosystem. You've got to build the
capacity in the supply chain infrastructure before the market arrives. This is why the ecosystem
matters so much. And it matters a lot here in Taiwan, by the way. Now, one of our most important
partners at Marvell in this journey has been Advanced Semiconductor Engineering, or ASC.
Now, ASC is one of the world's leading semiconductor manufacturing companies.
They're more than 100,000 employees with operation in Asia and actually all around the globe
with a decades-long track record of helping enable pretty much every major technology transition
we've gone through in the semiconductor industry. Now, leading ASC through this period of transformation
is someone that I know quite well. He spent more than 25 years helping shape both the company
and the industry. Today, I'm thrilled to have my next guest speaker come up,
which is ASC CEO, Dr. Tian Wu. Tian, please join me on the stage. Thank you.
Tian, how are you? Thank you for inviting me to Computec.
Great to see you. It's an honor to have you on stage with us. Well, it's my honor.
Look, we've been working together a long time. When I became the CEO, we had a set of ambitions.
We talked to a lot of our suppliers. I've known you even before I was the Marvell CEO,
when I was executive back at Maxim and we worked together there. But part of what it may be explained
to the audience too that sometimes people don't realize is that as a key supplier into this ecosystem,
you have to make bets. You've got to make bets on the companies you work with. You've got to
make bets on who you think is going to be successful. And we really appreciate that ASC bet on Marvell
very early, very early. And we've seen great success actually based on that. But I'm just
curious if you could share your perspective maybe on where Marvell was, what your thought
process is, and then where are we today in our journey together. So be great to hear from you,
Tian. Thank you. Okay, I think the best way to describe this is a gradual process. The first
decision was not difficult. Marvell Fabulous Company has a very good reputation, has gone
through a lot of transition. So the track record on Marvell has already been there. The product set
was a little bit obsolete at the time when you joined. So the first one is the business model
needs to be aligned. Taiwan ASC is in the manufacturing sector. So we're looking for bet,
not only on betting on your success, we're also betting on somebody who can provide the insight
for the next generation architecture and also the technology requirement. I see now the Taiwan
company invests infrastructure and cat packs 10 years ahead of time. Big bet. We're only counting
on whatever capacity we put it in. We'll be needed and we'll be utilized. That's how we make money.
So betting on company that we believe will give us very good insight well into the future
becomes very important. So that's how the decision was made at the very beginning.
And for the last 10 years, I'm just really happy. Everything that we talked about, it was a dream
10 years ago. It was a dream. And today we are going to ship it. And you just mentioned that
you're going to have 40% growth for the next few years. I believe you're going to be that.
So we're busy now preparing the capacity for you. We also appreciate that over the last 10 years
we have gone through a lot of strategic discussion. You make commitment to us. We make
investment for you. And over time, we're going to produce more of your parts. I think that's
the really a short story for how that decision will come. Yeah, no, it's been a great story.
Maybe one more for you. The ecosystem here in Taiwan is so unique. And like you said,
it takes like a decade of investment before you really can see the return. And there's just such
a power that's happening here. How do you describe it to the people here? And also there's a lot of
people around the world watching. And then what makes it possible here? Why is it unique? And
then what also makes it difficult to replicate this in the rest of the world? But at the same
time, there's globalization. So how do we think about those dynamics? I think that'd be an interesting
one. I think the reason why you're asking the question is there's a lot of competing forces
and also uncertainty across the world. So I think my belief is any business
needs to have vision as well as long-term alignment on value. So in the business model,
the whole Taiwan sector is built on capacity utilization and also innovation and technology
investment way ahead of the curve. That's what Taiwan is valued. So with the Fabulous Company
or with specific IDM company that business model aligns. Beneath that will be the economy of scale.
Taiwan cumulated 40 years based on the PC transition to the wireless to the mobile computing
to the data center. Now we're into HPC. So that 40 years of experience cumulated 350,000
semiconductor employees also cumulated 1.1 million high-tech employees and many of them are here.
That experience becomes extremely valuable combined with the economy of scale as well as
the cluster efficiencies. So when you think about the workforce with years of experience behind it,
when you think about the cluster efficiency, when you think about the capacity economy of
scale we already put it in. But one more thing, I think Taiwan good or bad, we had fewer choices
than the other region like the United States. So most of the engineer when they come out,
they have few choices to make. Semiconductor IT industry becomes a attractive choices in Taiwan,
not necessarily in the other region. So with all of this combined, I think this ecosystem
is very, very difficult to replicate. It is not impossible, but will take years.
Great. Well, thank you so much. I appreciate the partnership so much.
I appreciate it. Thank you.
We're off to the races. Tian, thank you. Tian Wu.
Thank you.
Okay. So like we said, the future of AI data centers is all optically connected infrastructure.
And you heard him say it, right? This is going to drive a tidal wave of growth,
innovation that's needed in scale and manufacturing. But what does that inevitable future actually
look like? I mean, if you just take a step back for a minute and you actually don't think about
right now, think about 10 years in the future. And it's a world where a lot of the copper connections
are gone. And just think about a world where data transmission now at some point is all optical.
This is a world where then distance doesn't matter, actually. And that's a profound change.
Servers, racks and overall data center architectures today have all been designed around the
constraints of distance. And software workloads actually have also been optimized around those
same constraints. But what if distance no longer matters? How might the architecture itself change
and what new capabilities become possible when the infrastructure is no longer constrained by
distance? So let's start with the scale up network in the rack. As we discussed earlier,
this is where we can connect the largest possible number of processors together in a full any to
any configuration. Now in the past, the size of this domain was limited by the length of the
copper connection, but with optics distance doesn't matter. So now we can change the size of the
scale up domain from 72 or 144 xpus or GPUs to 1000 or more, all optically interconnected.
The implications for workloads are enormous. Today AI workloads must be broken down into
smaller sub problems that fit within the scale up cluster, because communicating outside the
cluster today is slower, much lower bandwidth. But optically interconnected systems can manage
workloads on an order of magnitude larger. And it does not stop there, by the way.
What happens when the optical connectivity comes inside the server itself?
Modern AI servers are composed of a certain number of CPUs, xpus memory and network interfaces.
And the reason they're all in the same system is because of distance.
CPUs and xpus need to access memory at very, very high bandwidth, which means they need to sit
right next to each other on the board with copper traces serving as the connections between them.
But in a future where these connections are all optical, distance actually doesn't matter.
You can imagine a completely disaggregated architecture.
xpus in one system, memory in another, agentic CPUs in another, which unlocks another possibility.
In today's systems, the ratio of CPU and xpu or GPU, it's fixed. So these ratios have to be defined
at the time the system is built and deployed. But no two workloads require exactly the same
ratio. Jensen talked about this, actually, which means at any given time, some portion of the
computer memory could be underutilized for a given workload. That costs money. But once we
decompose the system into separate pools of compute and memory, and they're all optically
interconnected, we can then decompose dedicated systems on the fly, which are then optimized for
whatever the workload is. So imagine future data centers. A globally optically interconnected
data infrastructure. These rigid boundaries we have today in the systems we have,
they begin to disappear. Compute can now be pulled. Memory can be pulled. An infrastructure can be
composed dynamically at scale. For the first time, architects can begin designing AI systems
around the needs of the model, not around the limits of the interconnect.
So this is where AI infrastructure is headed. It's a data center without distance, where compute,
memory, networking, and photonics operate as one unified system. Where millions of resources
across the data center can work together as if they were one machine. An architecture defined
by the needs of the workload, not the limits of the connectivity. We believe this is the next
era of computing infrastructure, and Marvell is helping build the connectivity foundation
that will make all this possible. Thank you very much for your time today.
So
you